Iulian Plamadeala

Senior Software Developer

Summary

Senior Software Developer with Java, Kotlin, Flutter, and Node.js experience. Most of my career has been spent working on Android apps and Cross-platform projects. Versatile Software Engineer with expertise in Android, including AOSP (Android Open Source Project) and Android TV development, and with expertise in Cross-platform projects developed in Flutter, Firebase, Node.js, and MySQL, among others.

Professional Unity 2D/3D Game developer with a strong background in creating immersive and interactive games. Strong skills and passions for GAMES!

Contract

piulian@hotmail.com LinkedIn Web Site

+1 (613) 751-8039 Stittsville, Ontario, Canada

Programming Languages

Java

Kotlin

Dart

C#

JavaScript

C++

Lua

Python

Skills

Android Development

Cross-platform Development - Flutter

Back-end development - Node.js

BaaS - Firebase

Database - MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Agile / Scrum Methodologies

Algorithms

Creative Problem-solving

Object-oriented Programming

Android Studio

Unity, Unity Multiplayer Games

Cocos2d & Cocos Creator

Work Experience

Senior Mobile Developer

Sunshine Full-time

October 2022 - Present

Palo Alto, California, United States Remote

- Developed several cross-platform Android and iOS apps in Flutter
- Refactored the source code for an app that helps to reduce users' mobile traffic
- Updated the apps' target API level to meet the requirements of Google Play
- Created mobile applications that adhered to iOS and Material Design standards

Mobile App Developer

ActiveHealth Management, Inc Full-time

May 2021 – October 2022

New York, United States Remote

- Worked on logical modules to log health-related data, including sleep, diet, blood pressure, and exercise
- Build the payment and recognition feature on both iOS & Android
- Worked on Node.js & Flutter & Firebase
- Designed a back-end for the front-end to move slowly app logic to the API and improve app performance
- Added many native libraries including camera and gallery

Unity Game Developer

Zlodey Studios LTD Full-time

September 2020 - May 2021

London, Greater London, GB Remote

- Creation of prototypes, full game development cycle from concept to release, market research, competitor analysis, reverse engineering of projects, creation of marketing materials, mentoring
- Part of York Knight: Tower defense project

Game Developer

PlayMax Games Full-time

February 2019 – September 2020 Surat, Gujarat, India Remote

- Developed mobile games
- Created simple custom shaders
- Publishing the games on different stores and machines.
- Sharing, exploring, and learning new things technology, programming aspects, etc.

Android Engineer

Cronos Technologies Full-time

October 2016 – February 2019

Bucharest, Bucharest, Romania Hybrid

- Worked on Flutter, and associated with mobile app development including various aspects like coding, testing, client communication, and requirement gathering
- Explored new technologies and frameworks as a part of a Java innovation and architecture team
- Manage multiple projects to make sure they meet a deadline

Mobile Developer

Appscend Full-time

September 2014 - October 2016

Bucharest, Bucharest, Romania On-Site

- Part of Building Android apps (mobile & TV) to deliver video and audio content
- Provided support to the team whenever needed & help them understand their task
- Communicated with the clients and discussed on feasibility of adding new features
- Implemented the Android component of transfer-related cross-functional features

Android Developer

Orange Part-time

December 2013 – September 2014

Paris, France Remote

- Bug fixing and feature implementation
- Part of the Android OTT at Orange, developing Libon

Education

University of Bucharest

April 2010 – September 2014 Bucharest, Romania

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Language

English Professional Working Proficiency

Romanian Native or Bilingual Proficiency